

Brandon Davies

Web Designer

9 Wall St, New York, 10005, USA 890-555-0401 · <u>resumeviking.com/templates/</u>

Date / Place of birth 1989/20/03, New York Nationality

American

Driving license

Full

Skills

WordPress, Drupal, Joomla HTML5, CSS, JS, jQuery

Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator

Sketch

Time management

Deadline-driven

Effective communicator

Team player

Energetic and inventive

Profile

Energetic Web Designer with 3 years experience creating and maintaining functional, attractive, and responsive websites for travel companies. Clear understanding of modern technologies and best design practices. Experienced with WordPress and Drupal. Proven track record of raising UX scores and customer retention.

Employment History

Web Designer, Expedia Group, New York

January 2018 - May 2020

Expedia Group is a global travel company with websites which are primarily travel fare aggregators. As the Web Designer, my core activities included:

- Planning site designs, functionality and navigation, along with audience funnels and data capture points.
- Building wireframes & prototypes which were then turned into functional and responsive digital products.
- Reviewing UX with multiple teams and making necessary edits to accommodate technical or business concerns. Raised UX scores by 38%.
- Handling all composition, color, illustration, typography, and branding for projects.

Web Designer, FarePortal, New York

February 2018 - December 2018

FarePortal is a travel technology company where the flagship product CheapOair receives over 100 million visitors annually. As the Web Designer, my core activities included:

- Designing, building, and maintaining marketing email creative using data-driven responsive templates.
- Providing expertise on industry standards, best practices, and proper coding techniques to achieve correct rendering in all email environments.
- Performing quality assurance and troubleshooting code rendering across multiple desktop and mobile devices. Improved customer retention by 17%.
- Creating landing pages using WordPress CMS.

Web Designer, The Points Guy, New York

March 2017 - November 2017

The Points Guy is a site devoted to helping over 5 million monthly readers stay up to date on travel news. As the Web Designer, my core activities included:

- Creating homepage assets for both desktop & mobile experiences.
- Developing site content and graphics in partnership with writers and creative director. Spearheaded 4 projects simultaneously.
- Designing images, audio enhancements, icons, and banners.
- Presenting concepts and ideas consistent with company branding guidelines to the creative team.

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Interaction Design, Sterling College, New York 2016

• Excelled in UI/UX coursework.

Courses

Advanced User Interface Design, Udemy

May 2016